<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>book on Stanislav Myachenkov</title>
    <link>https://smyachenkov.com/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on Stanislav Myachenkov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smyachenkov.com/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>📌 Book Reviews</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Meta post for book reviews.
  Software Architecture: The Hard Parts: Modern Trade-Off Analyses for Distributed Architectures
  A Philosophy of Software Design
  The Staff Engineer’s Path: A Guide for Individual Contributors Navigating Growth and Change
  Understanding Distributed Systems
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Distributed Systems — Book Review</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-understanding-distributed-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-understanding-distributed-systems/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Distributed Systems: What every developer should know about large distributed applications, Second Edition is written by Roberto Vitillo and published on 23 February 2022 by Roberto Vitillo.
Structure Broad coverage of approaches and technologies of distributed systems. It leans more towards a practical side with a noticeable focus on troubleshooting, error handling, and resilience with a focus on web technologies.
There are five main parts:
 Communication Coordination Scalability Resiliency Maintainability  The Communication chapter overviews the modern network web stack, TCP, TLS, HTTP, and DNS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Staff Engineer&#39;s Path — Book Review</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-the-staff-engineers-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-the-staff-engineers-path/</guid>
      <description>The Staff Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Path: A Guide for Individual Contributors Navigating Growth and Change is written by Tanya Reilly and published on October 25, 2022, by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media.
Favorite Quotes  Early in your career, if you do a great job on something that turns out to be unnecessary, you’ve still done a great job. At the staff engineer level, everything you do has a high opportunity cost, so your work needs to be important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Philosophy of Software Design — Book Review</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-a-philosophy-of-software-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-a-philosophy-of-software-design/</guid>
      <description>A Philosophy of Software Design is written by John Ousterhout and published on July 26, 2021 by Yaknyam Press.
What is inside A Philosophy of Software Design explores best practices for code organization and decomposition, as well as common pitfalls to avoid in large projects where maintainability is a major concern.
A Philosophy of Software Design is a relatively short book that can be read in 1-2 sessions.
What is Good Strong first half with nice articulated ideas on:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Architecture: The Hard Parts: Modern Trade-Off Analyses for Distributed Architectures — Book Review</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-software-architecture-the-hard-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-software-architecture-the-hard-parts/</guid>
      <description>Software Architecture: The Hard Parts: Modern Trade-Off Analyses for Distributed Architectures is written by Pramod Sadalage, Mark Richards, Neal Ford, and Zhamak Dehghani and published on 23 September 2021 by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media.
What is inside Software Architecture: The Hard Parts: Modern Trade-Off Analyses for Distributed Architectures is a book about making a weighted decision during the design, redesign, or refactoring of the software system.
It is focused mostly on modern web-enterprise architectures and the popular dilemma of making a choice between monolithic and microservice architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
