<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>book on Stanislav Myachenkov</title>
    <link>https://smyachenkov.com/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on Stanislav Myachenkov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smyachenkov.com/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Philosophy of Software Design — Book Review</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-a-philosophy-of-software-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-a-philosophy-of-software-design/</guid>
      <description>A Philosophy of Software Design is written by John Ousterhout and published on July 26, 2021 by Yaknyam Press.
What is inside A Philosophy of Software Design explores best practices for code organization and decomposition, as well as common pitfalls to avoid in large projects where maintainability is a major concern.
A Philosophy of Software Design is a relatively short book that can be read in 1-2 sessions.
What is Good Strong first half with nice articulated ideas on:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Architecture: The Hard Parts: Modern Trade-Off Analyses for Distributed Architectures — Book Review</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-software-architecture-the-hard-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/book-review-software-architecture-the-hard-parts/</guid>
      <description>Software Architecture: The Hard Parts: Modern Trade-Off Analyses for Distributed Architectures is written by Pramod Sadalage, Mark Richards, Neal Ford, and Zhamak Dehghani and published on 23 September 2021 by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media.
What is inside Software Architecture: The Hard Parts: Modern Trade-Off Analyses for Distributed Architectures is a book about making a weighted decision during the design, redesign, or refactoring of the software system.
It is focused mostly on modern web-enterprise architectures and the popular dilemma of making a choice between monolithic and microservice architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
