<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Stanislav Myachenkov</title>
    <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Stanislav Myachenkov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smyachenkov.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Telegram Image Resize Bot</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/image-resize-tg-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/image-resize-tg-bot/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, I’ve had a project where I needed to have sets of images in different sizes. That was the only work with images in this project, and I did not want to bother with a complex image editor setup.
So, I’ve decided to create a simple telegram bot for quick image resize.
Telegram: https://t.me/resizerbot.
Github: https://github.com/smyachenkov/resizer_bot.
How it works First, you need to send an image. Both files and compressed images are supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Lambda And Telegram Bots: A Perfect Match</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/aws-lambda-telegram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/aws-lambda-telegram/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I want to create simple web applications, that automates one aspect of my life, try it and check if I will need it.
For this purpose, I often use telegram bots.
One-purpose project If you want to test an idea, you want to do it quickly and without extra layers of complexity. The closer implementation is to your pure, raw idea — the better. For simple projects, that are aimed to check if an idea even worth further development, you can safely ditch out staff like authorization, monitoring, or telemetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Presentation Tips</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/code-for-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/code-for-slides/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, I need to show some code in my slides. It can be an internal presentation for 3-5 developers, an online meetup, or a live event. And many times, I have found myself trying to recover the lost code style configuration or to recreate a color palette from the previous presentation.
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to save all the templates and share them and some tips about code in slides with you. I hope it will help you to create code slides quicker and better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Compare JSON Documents In Java</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/json-difference-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/json-difference-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Lets think about a task, where we want to know the difference between 2 or more JSON documents. We may want to do it to display the history of edits of the document to review, validate, and have a chance to roll back these changes.
For example, if we have two documents describing the movie Titanic:
{  &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Titanic&amp;#34;,  &amp;#34;length&amp;#34;: 195,  &amp;#34;genres&amp;#34;: [&amp;#34;romance&amp;#34;],  &amp;#34;cast&amp;#34;: {  &amp;#34;Jack&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;James Cameron&amp;#34;  } } and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Biases In Software Development</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/cognitive-biases-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/cognitive-biases-software-development/</guid>
      <description>A couple of years ago, I started my first job as a programmer. On the first day, I entered the office, sat in my new chair, turned on the computer, checked out a project from the version control system and opened it in IDE. The first-ever piece of the code I saw looked like that:
 // TODO it works, but it&amp;#39;s ugly, rewrite function init() { 	// some code } As you may already have guessed, this code remained untouched for a couple of years, until the project became obsolete and was archived and longer used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flyway Migrations in Multi-Module Maven Projects</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/flyway-migrations-in-multi-module-maven-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/flyway-migrations-in-multi-module-maven-projects/</guid>
      <description>Single migration set for multiple projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Static Analysis Tools</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/kotlin-static-analysis-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/kotlin-static-analysis-tools/</guid>
      <description>Kotlin did an amazing job saving and including into its scope most of all valuable Java libraries, frameworks, and tools. But there is one type of tool that can&amp;rsquo;t be easily imported and reused — static code analyzers. Java developers have implemented a lot of tools for code analysis, therefore, if you have worked with Java you might be familiar with some of the following projects: PMD, checkstyle, findbugs, spotbugs, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number of Categories for K-Means: Elbow and Silhouette Methods</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/number-of-categories-for-k-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/number-of-categories-for-k-means/</guid>
      <description>K-Means is a very common and powerful clusterization algorithm widely used in an unsupervised machine learning tasks for dividing data into categories. The only decision you have to make is the number of clusters you want your data to be divided into — k number.
Sometimes you already know how many categories you need to have. It depends a lot on the type of your problem, your data, and the problems you are solving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categorizing Instagram Tags with K-Means</title>
      <link>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/categorizing-instagram-tags-with-k-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smyachenkov.com/posts/categorizing-instagram-tags-with-k-means/</guid>
      <description>Choose a perfect tags for Instagram with machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
